Shubham Gulati

Senior Software Engineer • Certified Cloud Architect • 7 Years Experience • B.Tech & M.Tech Waterloo, ON • linkedin.com/in/iamshqulati • shubhamqulati.com

PROFILE

Shubham is an award-winning Senior Software Engineer with 7 years of exceptional IT experience at industry leading U.S. and Canadian professional services firms. He has a Masters degree in Computer Science & Engineering and is certified in AWS. His core competencies include cloud-native web application development using Java, Spring Boot, and Microservices.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Technology Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2022-2022

- ◆ Lead a team of junior developers that enhanced the ease of use and accuracy of a reporting application by 30%.
- Streamlined the development and improved reliability of system by promoting and following engineering best practices.

Technology Consultant, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2019-2022

- Developed the client's customer-facing portal with critical features like software licensing, entitlements, and downloads.
- Reduced technical debt for the project by developing a common foundation for 20 different microservice modules and JPA.
- Reduced the risk of security incidents by designing a framework to fetch configuration secrets from HashiCorp Vault.
- Improved the performance of business-critical features by 25% by optimizing application code, database tables and queries.

Technology Analyst, Deloitte Consulting

India - 2018-2019

- Developed client's HR Portal which was a regulated product with highly sensitive data and numerical operations.
- Reduced the operational costs of the portal by 20% by re-writing Coldfusion application using Java & Spring Boot.
- Improved the efficiency and security of the modules by 80% by re-architecting backend services for the cloud.

Associate Software Engineer, CGI Inc

India - 2016-2018

- Developed a framework to manage the state of system which reduced the maintenance downtime by 95%.
- ◆ Migrated SOAP web services to REST endpoints using modern Spring Boot-based microservices.
- Improved code coverage during testing through unit tests for Spring Web services using Junit and PowerMockito.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Developer Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)
AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)
AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Pursuing FPDELC1KXFF1QXK5 JJMV6422RJ1Q1NWV

SKILLS

Backend – Java, Microservices, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Web, Spring Security, SQL, ORM, JPA, Hibernate, REST

- Git, Junit, PowerMockito, GraphQL, Jetbrains IDEA, SDLC, Agile, Scrum

Infra / Cloud – AWS (EC2, S3, DynamoDB, CloudFormation, IAM), GCP, GitHub Actions, Docker, Jenkins, SonarQube

Security – pfSense, GVM, Nessus, Cryptography, PKI, Risk Assessment, Threat Modelling, Ghidra, IDA, Reconnaissance

Frontend – SSG, SSR, Typescript, React, HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, Next.js, Astro.js, Jetbrains Webstorm

August 24, 2024 Shubham Gulati • Résumé 1 of 2

EDUCATION

| Master of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology | | | | |
|--|---|------|--|--|
| Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology India | | | | |
| AWARDS | | | | |
| Conestoga | - High Distinction Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Computer Application Security. | 2024 | | |
| Conestoga | - Best of Program Award, Best Capstone Project in Computer Application Security program. | 2024 | | |
| Saskpoly | - Dean's List Award, Outstanding academic achievement in Cloud Computing & Blockchain. | 2023 | | |
| Deloitte | Applause Award, Technical contribution to the success of the eCX project. | 2022 | | |
| Deloitte | Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the STAR Migration project. | 2020 | | |
| Deloitte | Outstanding Award, Technical contribution to the success of the HRAlly project. | 2019 | | |
| Deloitte | - Applause Award, Project delivery excellence during the development of the HRAlly project. | 2019 | | |

Waterloo, ON

Saskatoon, SK

2019

2018

2017

PROJECTS

Deloitte

Deloitte

CGI

| Blog | - | Self-taught React, Typescript, TailwindCSS, Next.js, and Astro.js to build a blog with a simple design. |
|-------------|---|--|
| OSCAR | - | Secured Maven build supply chain for OSCAR, an open-source Canadian Healthcare EMR system. |
| Emoverse | - | Built a full-stack journaling platform using AWS serverless services, and fully automated CI-CD pipeline. |
| SmartDegree | - | Built a DApp to issue digital certificates using Solidity and Web3 and deployed on Ethereum blockchain. |
| DevMyMacX | - | Self-taught shell scripting to automate user and developer environment setup on a fresh macOS install. |
| DevMyLinuX | - | Self-taught shell scripting to automate Arch Linux OS and environment setup with minimal user interaction. |

- Apex Award, Unsupervised delivery, and individual contribution to the M2M GDSP project.

PUBLICATIONS

Research Paper

• An efficient technique to control road traffic using Fuzzy Neural Network System.

Postgraduate Certificate, Computer Application Security, Conestoga College

Postgraduate Certificate, Cloud Computing & Blockchain, Saskatchewan Polytechnic

- Spot Award, Critical support during CSP 2.0 project go-live.

- Applause Award, Delivery excellence during CSP 2.0 project development.

• Published in the IEEE Journal – https://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICRITO.2014.7014723